Matthewlowe1998@gmail.com 082 075-0087



Profile

Having completed my degree, I am looking to move into a Cyber Security or Development career path.

I **qualified to complete my degree in Australia** through a study abroad program with Monash. In order to do so I had to meet a minimum requirement of 60% and not have failed a unit in the first two years of my degree. Doing this gave me the opportunity to study units, I would not have been able to do so if I stayed at Monash South Africa.

Leadership and project management—I have taken on a leadership role in a number of group projects throughout university and was the Project Manager for our final year Industry Experience project. This has taught me the importance of accountability and responsibility.

Problem solving – I believe that this a strength and one that lends itself to the types of roles that I am considering. I have the ability to be resourceful when needing to find solutions.

Tenacity – I don't give up. I honestly have a mindset of getting things done.

Continuous learning - Over and above my current work, I have done a number of self study online courses through Udemy. This ongoing personal development is key to staying relevant in the market and to add value to any employer.

Qualifications

Qualification	Institution	Date
MS-100	Microsoft	July 2020
Bachelor of Computer Science	Monash University	2019
Matric	Northcliff High School	2016

Online self learning courses, including:

- Complete python bootcamp
- Linux for beginners
- Linux for security
- The complete NMAP ethical hacking course
- Security+ through Cybrary (for which I am still looking to take the exam)

LinkedIn Learning Courses Completed			
Power BI Essential	Windows 10 Security		
Ethical Hacking: Malware analysis	Windows 10 Administration		
Cybersecurity Foundations	Windows 10 Networking		
Incident Response Planning	Office 365 for Administration		
Teamwork Foundations (2015)	Conflict Resolution Foundations		
Writing Customer Service Emails	Creating a Positive Customer Experience		
De-Escalating Intense Situations	Getting Things Done		
Communication Foundations	Phone-Based Customer Service		



Matthewlowe1998@gmail.com 082 075-0087

Innovative Customer Service Techniques	Help Desk Handbook for End Users: PC Basics,	
	Hardware, Operating Systems, and	
	Applications	
Building Your Technology Skills	Learning PC Maintenance and Performance	
Achieving Your Goals		

LinkedIn Learning Courses in Progress				
Become a Data Scientist (Learning Path)	Become a CompTIA Security+ Certified			
Security Professional				
Data Science Foundations: Fundamentals	Azure Administration Essential Training			
Azure Essential Training for Developers	Microsoft Azure: Security Concepts			
Programming Foundations: Web Security	Learning Django (2018)			

Technical Skills

Key: 1 beginner – 5 expert.

Skills matrix					
Programming languages		Web frameworks			
Java	2	Django	1		
Delphi	2	CakePHP	2		
Python	3				
С	2	Data analytics			
C++	1	R	1		
PHP	1	Power BI	1		
Powershell	3	Excel	2		
Version control		Project management	Project management		
Git	2	MS Project	2		
	_	Trello	3		
Operating systems					
Windows	3	Databases			
Linux	2	Oracle	1		
		MySQL	3		
Security/Forensics		SQLite	1		
Kali	2				
Metasploit	1	Testing			
FTK Imager	2	Python	2		
		Jira	1		



Matthewlowe1998@gmail.com 082 075-0087

Career Summary

Company	Title	Date	
JEC Technologies	Intern	March 2020 to date	
MyPhysio (IE Project)	Project Manager	March 2019 to November 2019	
Self employed	Tutor	2016 to 2018	
Cliffview Primary Aftercare	Assistant	January 2017 to December	
		2018	
Promotional Staff Solutions	Promoter	April 2017 to March 2018	
Marketing 2 The Max	Promoter	January 2017	

Career Details

JEC Technologies as an Intern March 2020 to current

- Manage call on IT Service Desk
- Follow up calls
- Ticket creation, assignment and closure
- Documentation
- Daily server monitoring and backups
- Automation scripting and development for special projects
- Assist with project management of offshore developers

See projects worked below

Project Manager

Client: MyPhysio (Industry experience project)

March 2019 to November 2019

Overview

The group was tasked with **developing a website with a backend database and a front end**. It also provided **content management functionality** for the administrator as well as the ability to track system usage. We had to follow the full SDLC. The website was created to be an athlete management system where the main goal was to track performance and injuries. With three main types of users including:

- Player
- Coach
- Administrator

The player function was to track their performance and injuries.

Matthewlowe1998@gmail.com 082 075-0087



The coach was able to create teams and add players via email. They were then able to track which players in their teams are injured or ACWR (acute chronic workload ratio) was too high.

Responsibilities:

- Client requirements elicitation and documentation
- Responsible for some of the development and manual testing tasks (front and back end).
- Project Management including task allocation to team and review of Trello board
- Problem solving code errors
- Stakeholder management (feedback and engagement with clients through iterations)
- Compile project documentation
- Prepare and present iteration presentations to university and client
- Demo site to client and obtain project sign off

Technologies used

- MySQL
- Trello
- PHP
- CakePHP framework
- HTML and CSS

Self employed as a Tutor

2016 to 2018

- Tutor Math and Business Studies
- Prepare for lessons (review work, print extra work sheets)
- Record time at client
- Invoice clients

Cliffview Primary Aftercare as an Aftercare Assistant January 2017 to December 2018

- Supervise and assist with homework
- Lunch duty
- Register duty
- General play supervision
- Supervise swimming activity

Promotional Staff Solutions as a Promotor January 2017 to March 2018

- Stock and display analysis.
- Discussion with store managers and queries about stock.
- Placement of stickers, flyers and products as required.
- Take pictures of products in display.
- Draft and submit reports.

Matthewlowe1998@gmail.com 082 075-0087



Marketing 2 the Max as a Promotor January 2017

• Flyer promotion for Hi-Fi Corporation Woodmead

October 2017

Lenovo Telephone Campaign

- Called provided list of people to advise of update to event information
- Note nonattendance and any change of details
- Note incorrect contact details where applicable

JEC Technologies Projects

Project 1:

- PowerShell script to SFTP Covid results from a server to two locations by using Task Scheduler
- Testing
- Liaise with client

Project 2 (internal):

- Python and PowerShell script integration in order to total the Azure billing and convert to ZAR for each of the customers from the Microsoft Partner Center.
- Testing

Project 3 (internal):

- Script to update the contacts linked to a machine using PowerShell and ConnecctWise Automate
- Testing

Project 4 (internal):

- Power Apps and Power Automate to automatically create users for a tenant
- Testing